# Oliver Searle-Barnes

Passionate full stack leader Founder, CTO, VP Engineering, Architect 14 Years experience



FnCasts - watch me code on youtube



opsb - 200+ repos



opsb - 14 communities



opsb - top 2%

# INTRODUCTION

Building software that people actually like to use is what gets me going. With 14 years experience I've delivered successful products for the Telecoms, Retail, Publishing, Energy and Charity sectors. I've led teams to build a wide variety of projects including realtime social platforms and project management tools, business Intelligence, custom content management systems, online stores and browser extensions.

From day one I've been an agile practitioner, whether it's Scrum or Kanban, Lean, BDD, outside-in, pair-programming, you name it, I've been doing it for years. I've usually led from the front but I'm comfortable working in many different styles and value project consistency over personal preferences so am equally comfortable working alone or slotting into an existing team.

# **SKILLS**

years	years
Ruby on Rails 8	Event-sourcing/CQRS 2
Elixir / Phoenix 2.5	Scrum / Kanban 13
Elm2.5	BDD / TDD13
React/Redux 0.5	Git 10
RxJS1.5	Realtime systems 5
Ember.js5	HTML12
Javascript - ES2017 8	CSS / SASS 12
Java 5	0014
SQL 14	Functional 3
Firebase 2	Heroku 8
OLAP / MDX 4	AWS 8

### **OPEN SOURCE**

#### fncasts / fnchess

owner

Paired with a friend on youtube to build a chess game in Elm backend by Phoenix-Channels for realtime. See https://fncasts.io for the episodes.

#### orbitjs / orbit

core

A javascript library for orchestrating data synchronization. See **http://orbitjs.com** for more information.

#### saschatimme / elm-phoenix

core

Integration between Elm and Phoenix channels

#### opsb / elm-debouncer-fx

owner

An Elm effect manager for debouncing events

#### opsb / patchstream

owner

Emits ison patches as rails active records are updated

# **COMMUNITY**

I love to meet other developers and hear what they're getting up to. In Barcelona I'm a regular at the Elixir meetup and run the Elm hack night. I'm also regularly in London and Berlin so I make sure to pop into the local Elixir and Elm meetups there.

Online you'll regularly find me in the Elixir and Elm slacks. I've found both communities to be really friendly and helpful.

# **EDUCATION**

**Artificial Intelligence** 

2/1

Sussex University

2001-2004

# **EXPERIENCE**

# **TwentyBN**

#### Consultant

Sep-Nov 2018 Berlin / Remote

# Liqid

#### Consultant

Feb-Aug 2018 Berlin / Remote

# **Z**apnito

#### **VP Engineering**

2014-2017 London / Remote

# Lytbulb

2014-2015 London / Remote

#### Video Annotation Editors

Designed and built two Elm apps for collecting video gesture metadata from Amazon Mechanical Turk workers Elm, Javascript, Webpack

#### Salesforce Integration

Integrated a Ruby on Rails app with Salesforce using an Elixir/RabbitMQ based microservice Elixir, Ruby on Rails, RabbitMQ, Salesforce, Docker, GraphQL, Scrum, BDD

#### Feeds

Led the development of a realtime, embeddable social webapp

Phoenix, Phoenix-Channels, Elixir, Elm, Javascript, JWT, AuthO, Postgres, Webpack, Kanban, BDD

#### **Knowledge Networks**

Tech lead and architect for an expert focused content management system and online training platform Ruby on Rails, ember.js, Javascript, Postgres, Redis, Memcached, Solr, Kanban, BDD

#### lytbulb.com

Led development of a trello-like product aimed at the energy sector, focusing on oil and gas

Ruby on Rails, Ember.js, Firebase, Postgres, Kanban, BDD

# Myschooldirect

#### CTO

2010-2014 London / Remote

#### Give4Sure

A cross-browser plugin and webapp that helped charities raise money while their supporters shopped online Browser extensions, Ruby on Rails, Postgres, Ember.js, Kanban, BDD

#### Marks and Spencer School Uniforms

A collaboration with Marks and Spencer to provide bespoke school uniforms to UK schools Ruby on Rails, Postgres, Kanban, BDD

#### myschooldirect.com

A Quidco style shopping site where parent's could find deals that would raise money for their children's schools Ruby on rails, Postgres, Kanban, BDD

### Informa

#### Tech lead

2005-2010 London

#### **Intelligence Centre 2**

Custom CMS for analysis of the telecoms sector Java/Spring, Oracle DB, Scrum, BDD

#### World Cellular Information Service

BI portal for worldwide cellular market data Java, Spring, MS Analytics services, Oracle DB, Scrum, TDD

#### World Broadband Information Service

BI portal for worldwide broadband market data Java, Spring, OLAP, Mondrian, Oracle DB, Scrum, TDD

### **Nutshell Dev.**

#### Head of dev.

2004-2005 Brighton

#### Various local business websites

Built custom CMSs for local shops and restaurants Java, Spring, JPA, JSF, Mysql